# **Gabriel Fernandez**

San Francisco, CA 94131 · 415-515-2141 gabe.miguel.fernandez@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/gabriel-miguel-fernandez

Software QA professional with global experience creating processes and documentation to bring order to chaotic environments. Work in Agile teams to deliver SaaS products and features in a timely manner. Conduct manual tests of product features and write automated tests for APIs and web pages to improve test coverage.

#### **SKILLS**

### **Computer Languages**

(Familiar) C/C#, Java, JavaScript, Perl, Python, Ruby, Scala (Good) SQL, UNIX Shell

### **Operating Systems/Hosted Environments**

(Familiar) Android, AWS

(Good) iOS, Linux/UNIX, macOS, Windows 10/Server

## **Applications**

(Familiar) Cucumber, CVS, Git/GitHub, HP Quality Center, Hudson, Jenkins, Perforce, Pivotal Tracker, Selenium, Sikuli, Visual Studio, Zephyr

(Good) Confluence, JIRA, MS SQL, MySQL, Oracle DB, Postman, SQLite, TeamCity, TestLink, VMWare Workstation, Xero/Xero Payroll

# **Natural Languages**

German (9 yrs.), French (2 yrs.), Italian (1 yr.), Japanese (1 yr.), Russian (1 yr.)

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Xero,** San Francisco, CA **OA Analyst**, April 2013 - August 2019

April 2013 - August 2019

Tested Payroll products used in four countries: Australia, New Zealand, UK and US. Contributed to the release of new Payroll products for New Zealand, UK and US, and new features and frameworks for existing Australian Payroll product.

- Wrote automated Payroll API regression tests using existing test frameworks in C# and Scala, and using Postman in JavaScript.
- Documented test cases and test results in TestRail and JIRA that allowed others to
  consistently reproduce tests and track testing metrics. Wrote work instructions and provided
  reference Payroll data in Confluence, so that team members could quickly configure and use
  test tools and Payroll products as well as access test environments.
- Tested product features and bug fixes delivered in short Agile sprints using hosted and AWS test environments. Delivered features within timeframe. Coordinated testing tasks for releasing Payroll products to production environment.
- Managed releases for Payroll API and Timesheet services in the test, staging and production environments.

Kabam, San Francisco, CA

March 2011 - November 2012

**QA Analyst,** March 2011 - April 2012

Tested web-based Business Intelligence (BI) dashboard for game metrics, and monitored data quality. Also tested free-to-play gaming platform. Participated in feature design and sprint planning meetings.

Gabriel Fernandez Page Two

 Verified correctness of game metrics, tested scripts for data harvesting and processing, and tested BI dashboard reporting and graphing features delivered in Agile sprints.

- Investigated data quality issues involving harvesting and transforming data, from which base and derived metrics were generated.
- Provided technical support to BI dashboard users, and helped resolve cross-team issues.
- Used Pivotal Tracker and Zephyr to manage testing tasks and bugs.

## **QA Analyst,** April 2012 - November 2012

Tested Kabam and third-party games' integration with Kabam.com platform in mobile (Android and iOS) and web environments.

- Tested gaming platform features delivered in Agile sprints.
- Created automated UI tests for website using Cucumber in Ruby, and for Flash-based games using Sikuli.
- Managed testing tasks and bugs with JIRA, and test cases and test results with Zephyr.

# Vontu/Symantec, San Francisco, CA

August 2007 - February 2011

**Senior Software QA Engineer,** August 2007 - February 2011

Tested client-server software that scanned storage devices and monitored web browsers, e-mail and other means of transferring data for sensitive information based upon configurable policies.

- Tested product installations and verified documentation for UNIX servers and Windows PCs.
- Verified rule-based detection policies identified matches to regular expressions, CCNs, government IDs and indexed documents.
- Verified detection of policy violations for user events, e.g., HTTP, FTP, SMTP, IM chats, copy/ paste text, and copy/print/fax files; and for storing data in file systems and databases.
- Wrote automated tests using framework in Java that ran in VM test environments.
- Tested third-party applications that extracted text and metadata from files and email.
- Participated in feature design meetings, and product documentation reviews.
- Managed bugs with JIRA and Etrack. Also managed test cases and recorded tests results with TestLink and HP Quality Center.
- Trained new-hires and junior co-workers on product features and internal tools.
- Documented product configurations, test environments, test data and tools in internal wiki.

### Cataphora, Redwood City, CA

April 2004 - August 2007

**Senior Software QA Engineer,** April 2004 - August 2007

Tested C-Evidence, a web-based e-Discovery application for document review and research.

- Tested custom C-Evidence workflows for document reviews in a fast-paced work environment.
- Tested data extraction and processing tools that index files and email for document reviews.
- Wrote test plans, test cases, internal FAQs and how-to documents to share knowledge.
- Managed QA tasks for internal and client projects, and trained co-workers.

### **ADDITIONAL RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

Software QA Engineer, Walmart.com, Brisbane, CA

### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of the Arts, Mathematics** (International Studies Concentration) College of the Holy Cross, Worcester, MA